GABRIELLE WALD

(617) 413-0253 • gabibmello@gmail.com • LinkedIn: gabriellewald • GitHub: gabriellewald

SUMMARY

Data Scientist / Analyst interested in surfacing insights from data. Experience creating accessible visualization and predictive models for a wide range of applications. Passionate about the scientific method and the use of technology to generate positive impact, improve services, and discover solutions.

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn, statsmodel, seaborn, jupyter notebook
- Statistics: p-value, test for significance (z-test, t-test, chi-squared, ANOVA)
- Experimental Design: A/B testing, hypothesis testing, confidence level
- Predictive Modeling: logistic regression, lasso, decision tree, random forest, gradient boosting
- Data Science Methods: mining, wrangling, cleaning, analysis, visualization, storytelling
- Version Control: git, github
- Databases: SQL
- Languages: Fluent in English and Brazilian Portuguese

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Fellow, Springboard School of Data

Aug 2020 - Present

550+ hours of hands-on coursework, with 1:1 industry expert mentorship

- Created predictive model to understand student performance in CA K-12 public schools
- Formulated and tested hypotheses to understand demographic factors in performance
- Found and transformed several files to construct unique datasets
- Used machine learning algorithms in classification and regression models

Data Analytics and AI Fellow, DS4A Empowerment Program | Correlation One

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Merit-based fellowship with 5% acceptance rate led by Harvard Prof. Natesh Pillai

- Co-created capstone project to understand financial impact in CA K-12 public schools
- Ran regression models to determine variables of impact and identify confounding factors
- Performed t-test and chi-square analysis for hypothesis testing
- Conducted exploratory data analysis and created meaningful plots to identify patterns

Research Fellow, University of California Davis

Aug 2017 - Jul 2020

Data Analyst | SELF-lab

- Ran descriptives and constructed visualization for research in collaboration with the World Bank
- Organized and cleaned data with over 63,000 data points in R / Excel to prepare data for analysis
- Collaborated with researchers and participated in planning meetings

Research Assistant, Oakes Lab | Center for Mind and Brain

- Ran eye-tracking software SMI, collected and coded infant behavior data
- Screened participants and followed IRB guidelines for research projects
- Trained new RAs on lab procedures and collaborated with the research team

Research Assistant, Rivera Lab | Center for Mind and Brain

- Carried out data collection for behavioral studies
- Administered eye-tracking to study subjects
- Collaborated with P.I., PhD students, and fellow researchers

Vice President of Scholarship, PTK Honor Society International

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

- Partnered with organizations for collaboration on campus projects
- Led weekly meetings with society members to address action items
- Organized and presented induction ceremony to welcome new inductees

Language Tutor, University of Hawaii

Aug 2014 - Dec 2015

• Conducted tutoring sessions to assist students of English and Brazilian Portuguese with language assignments

Meeting the Standards Projection

May 2021

Education Project | Machine Learning Models

This project was an in-depth investigation of factors possibly affecting school performance

- Designed predictive model to project the percentage of students passing standard tests in CA K-12 public schools
- Modeled training data with linear regression, lasso, decision tree, random forest, and gradient boosting
- Combined multiple datasets and tested hypotheses to address open ended questions

EDUCATION

University of California Davis

2017 - 2020

- Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science, 3.65 GPA
- Computer Science and Neuroscience emphasis
- Relevant coursework: Applied Statistics, Biostatistics, Statistical Analysis in R, Linear Algebra, Research Methods, Data Structures and Algorithms in Python, Object Oriented Programming in Python

University of Hawaii | Kapiolani Community College

2013 - 2015

- Associate of Arts in Liberal Arts, 4.0 GPA Valedictorian
- Applied Linguistics Concentration
- Leadership: Vice President of Scholarship at Phi Theta Kappa Alpha Kappa Psi Chapter

CERTIFICATES

- Data Analytics and AI Fellowship, 300 hours
- Machine Learning with Tree-Based Models in Python
- Feature Engineering for Machine Learning in Python
- Supervised Learning with scikit-learn
- Data Visualization with Matplotlib and Seaborn
- Statistical Thinking in Python
- Data Manipulation with pandas
- Intermediate SQL